<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Fair play for one's life: or, The sovereign preservative of the royal family, nobility, &amp;c. and, of the arts of physick, and surgery, and the apothecaries trade. By a gentleman of quality of North Britain.</title>
            <title>Fair play for one's life.</title>
            <author>Gentleman of quality of North-Britain.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1708</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 60 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 9 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A39546</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing F102AA</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC T72031</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99834481</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99834481</idno>
            <idno type="VID">38982</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A39546)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 38982)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1884:6)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Fair play for one's life: or, The sovereign preservative of the royal family, nobility, &amp;c. and, of the arts of physick, and surgery, and the apothecaries trade. By a gentleman of quality of North Britain.</title>
                  <title>Fair play for one's life.</title>
                  <author>Gentleman of quality of North-Britain.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>16p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>printed for M. Wotton, at the Three Daggers in Fleetstreet; and sold by J. Morphew, near Stationers-Hall,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>[1708?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-06</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-07</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-10</date>
            <label>Megan Marion</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-10</date>
            <label>Megan Marion</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:38982:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>
               <hi>Fair Play for One's Life:</hi> OR, THE Sovereign Preſervative OF THE <hi>Royal Family, Nobility,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            <p>AND, OF THE ARTS of <hi>Phyſick,</hi> and <hi>Surgery,</hi> and the <hi>Apothecaries</hi> TRADE.</p>
            <p>By a Gentleman of Quality of <hi>North Britain.</hi>
            </p>
            <q>
               <p>Non avidiùs ipſum Alexandrum, quàm Medicum in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tuebatur Exercitus: pro ſe Quiſ<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> dextram ejus amplexi grates habebant, veluti praeſenti Deo.</p> 
               <bibl>Q. Curt.</bibl>
            </q>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON:</hi> Printed for <hi>M. Wotton,</hi> at the <hi>Three Daggers</hi> in <hi>Fleetſtreet;</hi> and Sold by <hi>J. Morphew,</hi> near <hi>Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioners-Hall.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Price, Two Pence.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="2" facs="tcp:38982:2"/>
            <head>Fair Play for One's Life, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </head>
            <opener>
               <salute>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nited South-Britains,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>THE Bleſſed Union (which I hope will never die) ſtrugled in the Birth with Difficulties almoſt inſuperable. How violent were the Oppoſers of our Partnerſhip with you, whoſe Luxuries and Avarice will inſatiably prey on the common Stock; 8 or 10 Leaders of the Parties and Projects ſhall ſet on the deluded People, to worry the moſt Honourable Zeal to do Good, to ſerve and to ſave their Country! How immenſe is the Difference of our Manners? The Protection of Life and Property is the firſt Article of the Compact of Human Societies. Your moſt Eminent Phyſici<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ans and Surgeons have been publickly exploded by you, treacherous to the Patients, ignorant of all Diſeaſes and Medicines: the Collegiates have often remonſtrated the numerous and the powerful Cauſes of the Calamities of all the Ranks of the Nation. Are there any Gentlemen of Reaſon and Honour, able to detect the malignant Diſeaſe, and apply the Sovereign Remedy?</p>
            <p>But, the Day the moſt important Article of the Union was to be debated, a Petition of our Apothecaries was read for Permiſſion to practiſe Phyſick and Surgery. I had the Honour to be commanded to deliver the Reaſons of our Refuſal; That we are oblig'd to protect the Phyſicians and Surgeons Properties, as we muſt defend our own E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtates, and Titles, and Privileges: that, if we betray the moſt learned and uſeful Profeſſions, we ſhall by the Example deſtroy the Law and the Church; and in the Conſequence, our Univerſities muſt be a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bandon'd and the Eſteem and Purſuit of Learning extinguiſh'd; that the Libertinage will encourage their Trade to increaſe prodigiouſly, and at laſt, ſtarve one another; that Millions of Native and Foreign Empiricks will break in on their Employment, and complete its De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtruction.</p>
            <p>Strange! (my United <hi>South-Britains</hi>) the Hour of my Arrival to the <hi>Britiſh Parliament</hi> preſented me the Accompliſhment of our Prediction. My Kinſman, who had invited me to his Houſe, obſerv'd my Diſorder from the Fatigues of the tedious Journey, withdrew, and brought his Apothecary. This good old Gentleman, he ſaid, has advis'd our Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mily theſe Fifty Years, he has more Patients and Experience than ten Phyſicians and Surgeons in our Neighbourhood: Treats them from the Beginnings of all Diſeaſes; They are call'd in only in the moſt Dangerous near their End. I preſented him a Fee, as is our Cuſtom to our Lawyers and Phyſicians. He perſiſted refuſing to touch it. I declar'd moſt ſolemnly, I never will, while I live, be advis'd, when the Numbers and Prices of all the Medicines ſhall only pay the Reward; when I ſaw, paſſing your Streets, eight or ten Shops in every one, and the Prentices prattling and playing; no Preparation making, not a Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>medy compounded; they are more numerous than the Sick.</p>
            <p>I was ſurpriz'd when the good old Gentleman embrac'd me with the greateſt Affection, when he wept for Joy, that he liv'd to ſee one of my Quality endow'd with Wiſdom to preſerve my Life, and the gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rous publick Spirit, to aſſert the Safety of the Royal Family, Nobility, Gentry and People. 'Tis only our taking no Fee, ſeeming to adviſe for Nothing, gives us the abſolute Power in the Houſes of the Nobi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lity
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:38982:2"/>and Gentry, and makes us able to invade and oppreſs our Phyſick and Surgery. It is in our Power, (as you moſt wiſely foreſaw) to pay our ſelves two or three Guineas a Day in the Wealthy, and one in the ordinary Houſes, above the real Values of the Remedies, to conti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nue it uninterrupted to the Recovery, and vaſtly above the Fees of the Phyſicians and Surgeons, who are call'd in late in the deplo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rable Caſes, have their ten Shillings only every other Viſit; when the Life is imagin'd in leſs Danger, they muſt often attend without any Reward to prevent the Relapſe, to ſecure the Recovery.</p>
            <p>My dear United <hi>Britains,</hi> I cannot expreſs my Grief and Confuſion. My firſt Reflection painted to me almoſt all the Phyſicians and Sur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>geons, treacherous to the Sick, and ignorant of all Diſeaſes, and the juſt Uſes of the Medicines. I importun'd my good Apothecary, who I perceiv'd, deſir'd the Redreſs of theſe terrible Grievances, to report the Diſeaſe and the ſpecifick Remedy. My Servant attended to take our Diſcourſe, to be publiſh'd in a Sheet, as the Sermons, the cheap Anti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dote and Preſervative of all the Inhabitants of the Iſland.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>N. B.</hi> I have heard, that (<hi>Ann.</hi> 1639.) the College reported the moſt weighty Affair to our moſt religious and learned K. <hi>Charles</hi> I. in Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cil, all the Judges commanded to attend. The Attorney-General was directed to revoke your Charter; your Shops were to be adjuſted to the Proportion of the City. The Rebellion prevented the Regulation. Your Phyſicians after the Reſtoration, publiſh'd many Learned Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>courſes on the Subject, they and the Surgeons have often addreſs'd, not for Preferments and Penſions, but the Cure of the Vileneſs and Deſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciencies of the Arts for the publick Service.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>S. B.</hi> Our Advice and moſt diligent Attendance of all the Sick in the Families of the Nobility and Gentry, being paid by our Bills, of as many Doſes as we pleaſe, and at our own Rates, greatly exceed the Sums they are able, or willing to expend, to preſerve their Health and Life. The Phyſicians Fee, (we will ſuppoſe the Surgeons are in all Points equally concern'd) is, when ſuperadded to our Load, the moſt intolerable Burden. It's our Intereſt to ſuggeſt the largeſt Fees, larger than they deſire, to make them odious to the People. This makes them dread the Phyſicians, 'till the Pains and the Dangers are moſt violent. Then they requeſt us to chooſe a Doctor for them. We will prefer none, but we can confide in, who ſhall juſtifie and commend all we have done, who ſhall patiently bear the Scandal of the Death: He is abdi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cated for ever, we advance another on the next Occaſion; we are never turn'd off, but by one of our Prentices ſetting up the next Houſe, and prevailing on the Stewards and Nurſes.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>N. B.</hi> Then farewel all the ſincere and learned Practice of Phyſick and Surgery. The ambitious or hungry Sollicitors of your Favour ſhall explode the Endeavours of the moſt generous Patriots of their Country to preſerve the Royal Family, the Nobility, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and your Trade as well as their own Profeſſions. Why are you on the ſudden pale and diſturb'd?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>S. B.</hi> By Heavens! we have carry'd the fatal Jeſt too far, we are un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>done. The Peoples Affection, as the Fondneſs of an indulgent Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, betrays us to our Ruin. We have our Prentices forc'd upon us to have the Title of Doctors, to practiſe Phyſick and Surgery, and the Apothecaries Buſineſs. We have this Hundred Years from our Charter, <hi>Ann.</hi> 1616, by two or three Prentices increas'd to an immenſe Number, filling all the Streets with eight or ten, as you obſerv'd, and three or four in all the Villages about the City. Our Gentlemen never think, or to no Purpoſe, for themſelves or us. Our exceſſive Increaſe muſt infallibly
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:38982:3"/>compel us to bring them more Medicines in all Diſeaſes whatever, and, from Year to Year, to raiſe the Prices of the Doſes. The Payment grows more and more oppreſſive, the Phyſicians and Surgeons muſt be more fear'd and abhorr'd, and inſulted, when they crave to be heard. But why do they not ſave and reſcue us from ten Thouſand Empiricks ſtarting up here, and from all Parts of the World, who take the Bread out of our Mouths? The buſie or hungry Clergy ſet up with their ſecret Cures. An horrible Number of Nurſes undertake the Manage<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, with their own Remedies, of all the <hi>Fevers, Small-Pox, &amp;c.</hi> The Quacks of the Advertiſements deal with their ſingle Preparations to cure infallibly this, or the other terrible Diſeaſe, or pretend it ſhall cure forty or fifty as ſurely as one; they make the moſt dreadful Ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vock of the Sick and us. How many Pretenders live plentifully by the Sale of <hi>Elixirs, Spirits, Tinctures, Pills</hi> and <hi>Cordials;</hi> the Papers of their Vertues and Uſes pedlar'd about from Houſe to Houſe? Then the Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tlemen of Quality, who pretend to top us on the Phyſicians and Surge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, beggar us without Mercy; they buy the <hi>Spirits, Tinctures, Laudanum,</hi> at the firſt Hand. We muſt ſtrive to make up our Loſſes by thruſting more of our Medicines on them, they ſtruggle againſt us, by thoſe, and many of their own Preparations, and take the Goa ſtone, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> from all the Viſitants. And (will you be able to believe it) there are many ſubtle Projectors of our Company, who have put off their Shops, have contriv'd to deſtroy me and my Brethren. They invade our Property; We ſhall not furniſh a Sea-Surgeon, our Brother, our Kinſman, or old Acquaintance, they muſt have their Cheſts at the Hall, more than they want, certainly dearer; and will you imagine them better than ours, when they are the moſt competent Judges of the Remedies they uſe?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>N. B.</hi> You ſee the neceſſary Tendencies of incroaching on one another. Do not the Magiſtrates know how the Publick ſuffers by the Inva<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſions of the ſacred Boundaries of the Profeſſions and Arts engag'd in the Preſervation of Health and Life? You have attempted the Regulations of the Law; the lurking Pochers of the Game are deter'd by the ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vereſt Penalties. It is now your turn to appeal, to implore the Prote<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction of the Government. Has not your Company reſolv'd to lay its own, and the Publick Diſtreſs before the <hi>Parliament?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>S. B.</hi> An Apothecary has in Print demonſtrated the Neceſſity of re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pelling the Empiricks, and of reducing our Numbers. He propoſes, That one Half may be oblig'd to ſerve the other as hired Servants. There are many of my Brethren (when the College has often deſir'd us to foreſee the Conſequences of our endleſs Multiplication) have in the Hall earneſtly recommended our uſing only Labourers to prepare our Medicines. I know many Surgeons, who lament with us the deadly Confuſions and Diſorders, and the neceſſary barbarous Ignorance of the modern Practice from the fear'd Deſtruction of the College. You know the ſovereign Medicine prepar'd by the Royal Martyr, and the Lords of his Council. You have ſeen the Diſcourſes of Dr. <hi>Goddard,</hi> Dr. <hi>Bates,</hi> Dr. <hi>Merret, &amp;c.</hi> and lately, the <hi>Diſpenſary-Poem,</hi> which remon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrates the Integrity and Learning of the Profeſſions ſinking more and more into the vain Preſumptions of Arrogance, or the humble Compli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance of uſing only the 30 or 40 vulgar Remedies of the Shops, contriv'd by Diviſions into numerous Doſes in all ſorts of Diſeaſes, to comple<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment our Choice of them, to raiſe for us out of every <hi>Fever, Small-Pox, &amp;c.</hi> 30 or 40 Guineas; out of the long Cures, 100, or 150. This you ſee is the only Title and ſtanding Army of our Power, and their ſlaviſh Subjection. As there are 3 or 4 Champions of our projecting Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, there are 8 or 10 Apothecaries gain their 1500, or 2000 Pounds a
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:38982:3"/>Year: We raiſe about as many Phyſicians and Surgeons, Bold <hi>Britons</hi> who ſtick at nothing. The Court, the Gentlemen of Quality, can never ſee their own, and the common Calamities, when their Phyſicians and Surgeons are preſented by us to them, pretending to the Learning in vogue, the empty Cyhimaera's and Romances of <hi>Hypotheſes,</hi> every day chang'd, and aſſoon out of faſhion, the Whimſies of the unſeen Moti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons and Operations of Atoms, nothing to the purpoſe of curing Diſea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes, or the Caſes of Surgery. And theſe unfortunate Gueſſers and Ope<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rators are commanded by us, to obſerve the Inſtructions we give them, to defy and damn the College and all the generous Attempts to preſerve the Publick.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>N. B.</hi> How many Thouſand Crimes form their Character? They muſt abjure their own Societies and Profeſſions, they muſt for the Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour of their Preferments, for their Salaries, expoſe their Patrons and the People to certain Death in all dangerous Diſeaſes, and carefully tranſmit to Poſterity theſe deteſtable Accompliſhments of their Arts.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>S. B.</hi> Will you allow, that they have reported almoſt theſe hundred Years, the moſt Learned and publick Spirited of the Society, the moſt troubleſome Diſturbers of the Publick, the moſt factious Reformers; that a Collegiate muſt be warily obſerv'd, and prevented, or expell'd from any Poſt of Publick Service. Shall the Royal College, Learning or Vertue flouriſh, when their moſt deadly Enemies infatuate the Gentlemen to fly from them, to aſſault their beſt Preſervers?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>N. B.</hi> Is it conceivable, that none of the Gentry ſhall be able to diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cover their true Intereſt, and detect the Impoſtors?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>S. B.</hi> When they leave the Care of their Wives, and Sons, and Daugh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters to the Nurſes and the Attendants, to us, and our Phyſicians and Surgeons, all theſe our mighty Grievances muſt grow in Stature and Strength. As the innumerable Empiricks, and the lurking Venders of Medicines multiply, we muſt enlarge the Numbers of Doſes, and their Rates; the <hi>Fevers,</hi> and <hi>Small-Pox, &amp;c.</hi> muſt produce the 20 <hi>l.</hi> to 40 <hi>l.</hi> 50 <hi>l.</hi> the Chronical, the 100 <hi>l</hi> or 200 <hi>l.</hi> How can I and many of my Brethren ſtint the Numbers and Prices, when every Year neceſſitates us to larger Numbers and Rates? When a large Part of us gain the Dr's Fee out of every Bole, and the Cordial-Draught to waſh it down; when 3 or 4 Guineas a Day are gain'd and 3 Papers of a Powder (worth 2 d.) ſhall produce almoſt the Guinea, muſt they not turnpale tremble at the Sight of a Phyſician and Surgeon. dreading we are laying our Taxations more heavily on them? Muſt they not implore us to keep them out to the lateſt Exremity, and then bring the Adviſer, who muſt enlarge the Account.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>N. B.</hi> I ſee theſe Gentlemen of the Faculties muſt ſtick at nothing; but what Methods can you and your devoted Phyſicians and Surgeons uſe to deſtroy the Phyſicians, whoſe generous Diſintereſt preſerves you, with their Society and Profeſſion?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>S. B.</hi> They ſhall aſſault them with the Rage of a Gladiator. Dr. <hi>G.</hi> has publiſh'd our Attempts on the Life of two of his Patients, to kill his Reputation with them. The pious Cabal of our Surgeons and Apothe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>caries, near our Cathedral, hir'd the Nurſe to affright and poiſon a Lady in the <hi>Small-Pox,</hi> with Child, on the ſame great Deſign. The Aſſaſſination was prevented by her Recovery, when their honeſt and skilful Management diſpatch'd to the Grave a Gentleman of the Houſe, a Party of the Company and Plot.</p>
            <pb n="6" facs="tcp:38982:4"/>
            <p>
               <hi>N. B.</hi> I am an Accomplice with them, I muſt take my part of the Guilt and the Puniſhment, if I do not in the next Parliament, lay the Univerſal Calamities before the Committee of the State of the Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion. We muſt, in the firſt place, protect you from the Numberleſs, moſt ignorant and daring Empiricks, from the ſly Pedlars of the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>medies. We muſt then preſerve you from being undone by your two or three Prentices in all the Shops. We cannot defend our Life, but by the juſt Proportions of the Medicines in the various Diſeaſes. We muſt betray our own, and the Life of all the People, we muſt aboliſh the Faculties in your two famous Univerſities, if we do not reſtore the Since<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity and Sufficiency of the Profeſſion, the moſt implor'd in the greateſt Diſtreſs by Mankind. The Gentlemen then of Great <hi>Britain</hi> will explode the perfidious Phyſicians and Surgeons, will detect the ignorance of the moſt Arrogant, will applaud the moſt honourable Zeal of the Collegiates, from the Addreſs to K. <hi>Charles</hi> I. in Council, to the mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dern Reformets of the moſt vitious Practice.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>S. B.</hi> You may pleaſe to add, who have been aſſaulted by our Out-Guards, our Phyſicians and Surgeons in all the Houſes about the Court, but when they preſented the Publick Calamities to the Lord Mayor and Court of Aldermen and the Common Council, and Our Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany unhappily rejected the Expedient, the <hi>Panacea,</hi> which can only redreſs the Confuſions and Malignity of the modern Practice, which the Committee had reſolv'd after long and the moſt mature Deliberations, the City requeſted the College to erect its <hi>Diſpenſaries.</hi> But we cannot live without the great yearly Payments from the Poor and the Wealthy: This gives us our Power, confirm'd more and more by the long and conſuming VVar, to raiſe to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ame, or ſtarve the Phyſicians. The Poem deſcribes our Champions aſſaulting the College, and the greateſt Part of the Diſpenſarians have been forc'd for Bread to revolt to us.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>N. B.</hi> The imminent Danger of the Invaſion will unite us, will rouſe our vigilance and Courage, when we reflect, that we muſt die in all the moſt ſafe and ſecure Diſeaſes, without Hope of Relief in the moſt intricate and ſevere.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>S. B.</hi> All the Profeſſions and Arts, the Serious and the Amuſing muſt be fed and led by the Hand in their Infancy, will conſpire in their Evi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dence, and aſſiſt us to make the ſureſt Judgment in the Cauſe. A young Gentleman buys a Commiſſion, he muſt be inſtructed by the Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficers, or learn from their Footmen and the Sutlers. The Profeſſors in the Univerſities do not inform the Students, what Authors give the moſt certain Obſervations of Human Nature, of the infi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nite Diſeaſes, which are expell'd by Nature alone, of the various Medicines and the Seaſons of applying them. The Phyſicians of many Years Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perience, with a Generoſity almoſt peculiar to the Profeſſion, were the moſt candid Patrons of the young Practicers. The young Arrogants now raiſe themſelves by inſulting their improv'd Learning, their Ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſervations of the Happy, or ill Succeſs of the various Methods and Medicines in all kinds of Diſeaſes. But they muſt have one or other to introduce them. Our Apothecaries of the different Deſigns, oblige them with the ſuitable Inſtructions. You muſt preſcribe the common Juleps and Boles, and three or four ſorts of Apozemes, from 30 or 40 Medicines, we have confin'd the Practice to. You muſt make the greateſt Pother with them, and Bliſters, and Scarifying, and Setons, to amuſe the Aſſiſtants. The greateſt Part in the common ſafe Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtempers will recover. You muſt pronounce every Eſcape a mighty Cure, ſhift off from a dangerous Buſineſs, but proclaim in all your Companies, you could have ſav'd the Life: If you find them reco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vering
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:38982:4"/>in 2 or 3 days, ſhew your Care, and damn all the Medicines be fore preſcrib'd. How different was the Practice, when I came firſt to the City? The Phyſicians from the Univerſities, examin'd and applau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded by the College (as the Clergy by the Biſhop) ſupported by the old Practiſers, viſited all the numerous Caſes of the meaner People in their Neighbourhood, as the Gentlemen of the Gown open the Cauſes, and adviſe in the Purchaces of leſs value. The proportion'd Fees, and the Cheapneſs of the Medicines, introduc'd them to all the Families. The Succeſs was aſſur'd by the frequent Converſe with the Patrons of the Art, by their Inſtructions or Conſultations in the moſt Important. We were not then their dangerous Rivals or declar'd Enemies. Our Shops were open to them, to confirm and improve their Skill in the Drugs, to examine their Qualities and Virtues, and Preparations, or to obſerve the Tryal of the New, or lately improv'd. The frequent endow'd Le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctures often conven'd the Collegiates. The Converſation diſcover'd the never-failing Methods to ſubdue the Epidemical malignant Fevers, the ſpecifick Medicines in the acute or moſt obſtinate Chronical Diſeaſes. They may now debate their own Diſtmpers, if the Diſpenſary Poem has truly drawn by the Inſtructions of the Preſident, the Characters of the <hi>Mirmils, Querpoes,</hi> the <hi>Bards.</hi> Will it therefore ſurprize you that we frequently foretel in the Chamber, that the Dr. we preſent to them, will order only this and the other Remedy, and Bliſters and Cupping, that the Gentlemen of Quality avow they can ſee no Difference, that their Apothecaries do as well as the moſt Arrogant? Shall the Gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral enter the Field to turn the flying Troops; or the Judge, when the Pleadings are ended? Can they ever underſtand a Diſeaſe, when they are brought in by us, when all the natural Powers are ruffled and bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken; when the fatal Symptoms are firſt diſcover'd by the Attendants?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>N. B.</hi> How eaſily are Fevers, as Fires, extinguiſh'h by timely Care? How eaſily are almoſt all Diſtempers prevented from the moſt dange<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rous Symptomes? Has the Royal Family, the Nobility, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> the Phyſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cians early Conduct? How ſhall they ever know the Manners of the Invaſions of Diſeaſes, their Advances, the Ravages they make of the Natural Strength, when they have loſt the ten Thouſand Caſes of the Patients near them, who muſt ſtand in the Front, receive the Shocks of Diſeaſes, and protect the Life of the Royal Family, and the Nobi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lity? When ſhall their Phyſicians begin to underſtand them, when all the Novices in all the Arts, are allow'd their Proportions of Defeats and Blun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders, eſpecially in the Practice which wants the experienc'd Patrons In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtructions and Cautions?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>S. B.</hi> When the natural Tendencies to collect and ſeparate the mor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tify'd Humors (by which only Life can be preſerv'd in all Diſeaſes) by the different Evacuations are aſſiſted, directed, or controul'd, if too vehement, the Diſeaſes ſhall be rendred more benign, the Ferments of the Humours to greater Malignities prevented, and a large Part evacu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ated the firſt Days, the Feeble remaining ſubdu'd by the internal Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of the Blood. When they are ſuddenly brought to the unhappy Turn of the Diſeaſe, what can we expect from their Obſervations and Advice only in the Morning, when after the Storm during the Night, all the Symptoms are allay'd? While the Medicines preſcrib'd are pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paring, they often begin to rage more violently, ſeize on the Brain, the Breaſt, the Bowels. The Medicines may be in the Evening deſtru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctive. The ſalutary Excluſion of the Humours may be fatally ſtopt, or the Evacuation fatally promoted by them.</p>
            <pb n="8" facs="tcp:38982:5"/>
            <p>
               <hi>N. B.</hi> I remember you aſſerted, That the Phyſicians are confin'd to 30 or 40 vulgar Remedies always ready in the Shop, to be mix'd and divided into the Doſes. I ſuppoſe, becauſe you are engag'd in the ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſing and attending your own Patients, and cannot attend to any new, or nice, or difficult Preparation, how can they apply them to the many different Indications of Cure?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>S. B.</hi> It's now thought unbecoming the Phyſicians to examine all the Chymical and Galenical Preparations, and ſelect the beſt of both. We have many Years paſt, deter'd them from that moſt neceſſary Part of their Art. We have therefore, often in the <hi>Court of Requeſts,</hi> and in the private Families, publiſh'd their lamentable Ignorance, that if they ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zard the Preſcription of any but the common Receipts, the Colours, the Scents, the Taſts, the Conſiſtences expoſe them to the Laughter or Pity of our Prentices, that they muſt be redreſt by us, before they are ſent to the Patients. And we may ſend in what Remedies we pleaſe, without the Dread of their Diſcovery of the Fallacy. You will be inform'd, that 6 Eminent Apothecaries Preparations, now of the moſt general Uſe, were condemn'd in our Hall, vilely ſophoſticated, wanting every deareſt Ingredient; that 3 or 4 Apothecaries ſupply'd the Army in <hi>Ireland</hi> with the moſt infamous Drugs, confeſt by the Druggiſt; that our Gentry often debate, whoſe Apothecary has the beſt Things; but our Phyſicians never diſtinguiſh, if the <hi>Bole,</hi> or <hi>Julep,</hi> or <hi>Powder,</hi> or <hi>Pill</hi> which are mixt by their Order, of 8, or 10 Preparations, are compounded of the beſt or the worſt Ingredients,, cannot be aſſur'd, if the <hi>Bark,</hi> the <hi>Laudanum,</hi> the <hi>Spirits</hi> or <hi>Tinctures</hi> are good; whether the Ignorance of the Diſeaſe, or the horrible Remedy prevented the Cure. The College lately voted the Neceſſity of compoſing a new <hi>Diſpenſatory,</hi> rejecting the worſt Preparations, and ſubſtituting the moſt rational and efficacious, which the improv'd experimental Philoſophy in all the other Parts of <hi>Europe</hi> has diſcover'd, but the modern Learning is of no Uſe to them and the People: Diſeaſe and Medicines can only be known by the moſt diligent Obſervations and Experiences.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>N. B.</hi> Are not the Gentry able to detect the Impoſture?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>S. B.</hi> They have many Years ſuſpected it; In almoſt all Diſeaſes, fly for Help to the experienc'd Preparations of their Families communica<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted to them, before our Phyſick and Surgery were corrupted and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bas'd. But when we and the Artiſts combine to diſguiſe the Fraud, how eaſily will the Amuſement prevent the Conviction? If the <hi>Fevers</hi> are attempted to be cur'd by <hi>Acids,</hi> the Chymical Corroſives are us'd, whoſe Force the Metals cannot reſiſt; they operate with too much Vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>olence, precipitate and colliquate the Blood. If by <hi>Alkalies,</hi> what Suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſs will you hope, unleſs the Conſtitution can expel the eaſie Diſorder, when 1000 Doſes may be taken without any ſort of Operation; and the <hi>Bezoar</hi> is demonſtrated by the beſt Phyſicians of the Age, and many late Experiments to be indiſſolvable, which the moſt corroſive Chymi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cal Spirits cannot penetrate. Not many Years paſt, 5 Medicines only pretended to conquer all Diſeaſes whatever, with our Cordials, deſign'd only to fill the vacancies.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>N. B.</hi> What are the Remedies we want?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>S. B.</hi> You know the <hi>Bark</hi> is a powerful Specifick in all intermitting Fevers, which mixt with the Blood ſubdues its efferveſcence, but it muſt be fatal, when the Humours are malignant and detain'd by it. The College therefore in the <hi>Poem</hi> complains, That the Art is dwindled into the meer Craft of deceiving the Sick with few vulgar Compoſitions; but it wants the generous Speciſicks or Alteratives, that the great En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quiries or the Recovery of them, have been lately expell'd the Practice.
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:38982:5"/>Dr. <hi>P</hi>—has in his Comments, explain'd the Deſign of the Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lege in that Publication, as my Lord <hi>Cook</hi> the Tenures of <hi>Littleton.</hi> Common Sence, as well as the Philoſophy of Phyſick will inform us, the morbid Humours are not always prepared to be evacuated by Sweat, by Urine, by the Bowels, that the vicious Qualities of the Blood muſt be reduc'd and diſpos'd for the Evacuation, by the Medicines of the con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary Qualities. The alteration of the Blood inflam'd, extremely Vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cious, fermenting with Violence, and preventing the collection and ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pulſion of the morbid Matter, or acid or watery, or roapy, or the Cra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſis broken, and the neceſſary Ferment too languid, ought to be the firſt Intention and Deſign of the Phyſician. Then he muſt warily obſerve the Progreſs of the Natural Efforts, and diſtinguiſh which of the dif<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferent Evacuations are choſen in the various Conſtitutions, then aſſiſt and promote, and direct the Excluſion, or moderate or repell the preci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pitate or exceſſive Evacuations.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>N. B.</hi> This is the moſt Soveraign Preſent Mankind can receive, if the Health and Life of all the Inhabitants, are of any value to them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves or the Publick; oblige me with a ſhort Report of it.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>S. B.</hi> The Comments Publiſh and Demonſtrate the 4 certain Prin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciples or conſtituent Parts of all Vegetables and Animals, which variouſly alter'd and mixt produce the Healthy and Diſeas'd Qualities of the Blood: The happy Application and Union of the Qualities of the Me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dicines cannot fail to reſtore the Natural and Healthy Craſis. They preſent us the abundant Plenty of the Degrees of thoſe Qualities mixt and compounded in the vaſt varieties of their Vertues, the Magazine of Medicine, Providence has provided to prevent and ſubdue all Diſeaſes. Chymiſtry has unfortunately attempted to improve them by ſeparating and deſtroying the Divine Compoſitions. The ſeparated Principles cannot unite with the Blood act on it with the moſt vehement Impreſſions, are only of the nobleſt uſe in the rare Caſes, when the Salutary Violence is demanded, as the <hi>Burnings</hi> and <hi>Inciſions</hi> of <hi>Surgery,</hi> are moſt neceſſary to inflame the languid Spirits and Blood, but they diſſipate and waſt, with themſelves flying off, the moſt active Spirits of the Blood and the Nerves. They are (the <hi>Vinous</hi> and <hi>Volatile Spirits,</hi> the <hi>Oyls</hi>) moſt neceſſary to enforce the Evacuations of Sweats and Perſpiration, to blow up the Vital Fire when almoſt extinguiſh'd, or (the <hi>Acid Spirits,</hi> the <hi>fixt Salts</hi>) to cool and repreſs the inflam'd Oyl of the mixture of the Blood. But how deſpicable is the Penury of Chymiſtry compar'd with the Riches and Magnificence of Nature. All the <hi>Vinous,</hi> and <hi>Volatile</hi> and <hi>Acad Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rits</hi> are but three Medicines differing only in the Degrees of one Quality. The <hi>unfermented Oyls</hi> are only diſcriminated by the being more or leſs di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>luted. All the <hi>fixt Salts</hi> are only varied by the Circumſtances of their Fuſion. The <hi>Magiſtcries</hi> and <hi>Calcinations</hi> are a deed unactive Earth. when you except the Preparations of the Minerals. The greater part of the Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditions of the <hi>crafty Arabians</hi> to the moſt rational Pharmacy are the moſt abſurd Medicines in the World. Moſt of the <hi>Conſervet</hi> and <hi>Sycups</hi> pretend only to prevent the trouble of preparing the moſt generous Remedies, the <hi>Extracts, Infuſions</hi> and <hi>Decoctions,</hi> but are the moſt oppreſſive in the Stomach, the moſt corroſive corrupters of the Blood. The largeſt Part of their Compoſitions is infamous from the horrible tumults of the contrary Qualities of 50, 100 Ingredients in one, controuling and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtroying one another's Efficacies.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>N. B.</hi> The moſt Self-evident and ſerious Truths! The noble Speciſick, the <hi>Bark,</hi> muſt be taken without Addition, Powder'd, or, infus'd or decocted, or extracted, ſhall it be debas'd by <hi>Sugar</hi> to a <hi>Conſerve</hi> or <hi>Syrup;</hi> or <hi>Diſtiled</hi> to a <hi>Simple vappid Water,</hi> or to a <hi>Brandy Spirit</hi> from a <hi>fermented
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:38982:6"/>Liquor?</hi> Shall the ſtronger Fire force over the <hi>ſtinking Oyl?</hi> The wonderful Compoſition of its Principles is vitiated or wanting, or corrupted by their brutiſh Cookeries of the <hi>ador'd Specifick.</hi> Surgery will uſe the Oyls, or the Subtilizations of them by Fermentation in the Vinous Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rits on the rare Occaſions, but the Fomentations, and all the other Topical confeſs their powerful Operations from the preſerv'd entire Qualities of the Vegetables. How ridiculous are the Purſuits of Chi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſtry, deſign'd only for ſurprize and the Pleaſures of Amuſement? How vain the Ambition to out-do by our Artifices the inimitable Maſter-pieces of Nature? How unhappy are the Great and Noble, poor in their Confinement to the enjoyment of the Trifles they reſerve to themſelves?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>S. B.</hi> The Alterative Specificks are the Medicines, which in all the Ages paſt, reſtor'd the moſt Difficult Diſeaſes to Health, by correcting the vicious Qualities of the Blood, by uniting with it and ſupplying the Principles defective in the reſpective Diſorders. The innumerable <hi>Fe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vers, Diſeaſes of the Brain, Breaſt, Bowels,</hi> the <hi>Viſcera,</hi> the <hi>Dropſie, Jaundice. Gout,</hi> the <hi>Scorbutical Colliquations,</hi> the Diſorders of the <hi>Sex</hi> can only be cur'd by the frequent uſe of their Alteratives in the proportioned Quantities, as the Waters, to dilute with the Efficacy of their Minerals. The Comments range them under the obvious Claſſes of their Qua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lities and Vertues, 1. The <hi>Aromaticks,</hi> the Acrid, Spicy or Cordial, the Reſtorers of the Oyl and internal Motion of the Blood, 2. The <hi>Aſtrin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gent,</hi> 3. the <hi>Bitter,</hi> 4. the <hi>Acid,</hi> 5. the <hi>Sweet,</hi> 6. The <hi>Watery.</hi> But the Wiſdom and Powers of Nature are boundleſs. The <hi>Aromaticks</hi> are more Acrid, or attemperated by the Aſtringent, or Bitter, or Acid, or Sweet or Watery Qualities, every other Claſs regales us with the ſame large A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bundance and Variety.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>N. B.</hi> You obſerv'd, That the more rare Indications demanded Blee<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding, the Vomits, Purgers, Sweaters, the Chymical Spirits, and the Vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nous Waters, to revive the Vital Flame. I have heard, a Sect of Phy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſicians has cur'd all Diſeaſes by the Alteratives you have deſcrib'd con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vey'd into the Stomach and Blood, with the Nouriſhment of our Foods, and the three laſt are avow'd to be reſtorative by Nouriſhment, and Me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dical, and Correctors of the Vicious Humours. Will not the Patients fear, that the dead diſtill'd Waters of the Fruits and Herbs, will turn their Blood into a Dropſie, that the fermented Spirit of the Grape, of all the Vegetables will evaporate and conſume the more active Parts of the Blood, the Spirits, and therefore every Hour raiſe the craving a new ſupply, till the Apetite and Digeſtion are deſtroy'd to a Dropſie or Conſumption? Will they command their Cooks to prepare the Fleſh with Sugar, or Diſtill it to a Simple or Compound Water? Will they feed on the Drops of the Oyl extracted from it?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>S. B.</hi> Not more than 3 or 4 Centuries are paſt, ſince the <hi>Arabian</hi> in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vented the Diſtillations. <hi>E<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ROTE</hi> long preſerv'd the uſe of the Spe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cifick Alteratives, the colluſions of the laſt Age made the fatal Deluge of the Simple and Compound Waters. The Eaſe and Profit of the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thecaries have abdicated the vaſt Numbers of them. Milk-Water and of Black-Cherries, and 3 or 4 of the Compound are only retain'd in ſervice. The Phyſicians are indifferent which of them make the Julep for the Head, Breaſt, or Stomach, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> The Evidences of the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments are irreſiſtable, from the atteſtations of all the moſt ſucceſsful Pra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cticers of this Age, who avow they only divert their Patients with the temperate Juleps, as Sweet-meats, and from the Philoſophy of all the kinds of Diſtillation, which can bring over no one Part of the great Natural Compoſition from any of the Specifick Vegetables
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:38982:6"/>but the <hi>Aromatick,</hi> and from them only the <hi>Oyl</hi> ſeparated from the other Principles. If there are 50 Plants in the Compound Water, and 25 <hi>Aromatick;</hi> you have 25 <hi>Oyls</hi> with the ſmatch only of the Qualities of the Plant: Every Oyl muſt vehemently inflame, raiſe the Nau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſea's and Flatulencies, and the Tempeſts of Wind they are pretended to break. The good Sence therefore of our Gentlemen and Porters prefer the <hi>Simple Spirit,</hi> or the Infuſions <hi>Rattafia</hi> and <hi>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ſquebaugh</hi> before them, and the ſureſt Succeſs in all the windy and Phlegmatick <hi>Colicks</hi> ſupports their Judgment. Shall our Arrogant Phyſicians and Surgeons be able to appoint none of the Appropriate Remedies, but theſe moſt of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fenſive Punches, in all the Hours of all the Diſeaſes of all the Conſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tutions and Ages? The Appropriate Alteratives, either the Watery Oyly, or the Watery Sweet, or the Sweet Acids, or the Acid bitter in the moſt a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>greeable Animal Liquor lately preſented from the moſt efficacious Plants of the Field, and the more agreeble Liquors, whoſe Oyls are attem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perated by the other Principles, ſhall abate every Hour the deputary Motion of the Blood in all the inflammatory Diſeaſes, reject a part of the Recrements, every Hour, by the Pores, by Urine or the Bowels, and gradually reduce the ferment to the Natural Temper, and make the juſt <hi>Criſis</hi> by Sweats, and the other Evacuations or the Cutaneous or Glan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dular Separations. When we ſhall have this and a thouſand other Reforma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions, the Phyſicians and Surgeons oblig'd to learn, and preſcribe the moſt uſeful Medicines, the Apothecaries carefully preparing the Reme<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy adapted to the Circumſtances of each Caſe and Conſtitution: The People will generouſly reward our Induſtry, we ſhall not inſult and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtroy the Profeſſions to make our Reprizals on them, becauſe Millions of Empiricks, the daring Privateers and Pirates on our Trade, invade and plunder us.</p>
            <div type="part">
               <opener>
                  <salute>My dear <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nited Britains,</salute>
               </opener>
               <p>I aſſur'd my good old Gentleman at parting, that War ſhall be pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>claim'd againſt the wicked Empiricks, that their Defeat ſhall give the firſt Triumph to <hi>Great Britain.</hi> Tho' they are as numerous as the <hi>French</hi> in <hi>Flandess,</hi> our Gentlemen of Honour and Vertue, (if every one cares only for himſelf) will bravely attack their Intrenchments, when their Courage ſhall be enflam'd, after reading the Memoirs of the Engliſh Practice, preſented to me by all the Phyſicians and Surge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons of Integrity. When the <hi>Arabian Chymiſtry</hi> had preſented to <hi>Europe</hi> the admirable <hi>vinous</hi> and <hi>volatile Spirits,</hi> and the <hi>Oyls,</hi> the <hi>acid Spirits,</hi> and the <hi>fixt Salts,</hi> which juſtly apply'd, exert the almoſt miraculous Powers; the firſt reviving the almoſt dead vital Flame, the other inſtantly ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinguiſhing the Fire of the Blood in the Doſe of few Drops and Grains: Millions of <hi>Empiricks</hi> peſter'd <hi>Italy, France, Germany:</hi> Every one pretended to his own Diſcovery and laborious Preparation of a ſupernatural Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>medy, each Drop demanded the Peice of Gold, the Reward of its Title and Atchievements: An <hi>Army</hi> of <hi>Empiricks,</hi> as the old <hi>Saxons,</hi> in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vaded our Iſland. The Princes and Nobility, (who is ſecure from the Enchantments of the Craft of Phyſick?) admir'd and applauded them, decry'd all the Learning, and Obſervations, and Medicines of the Pra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctiſers refuſing to rely on them in all the Diſeaſes of Mankind. The fiery Quackery triumph'd, 'till the Cheapneſs of their little Doſes was dete<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cted, were forc'd to load the Sick with the Proportions of other Me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dicines, which cou'd ſupport their Gain. The Manufactures flouriſh'd in all Parts: The Officers licens'd the <hi>Strolers</hi> of <hi>Plays;</hi> the <hi>Tumblers,</hi> the <hi>Monſters</hi> and <hi>Elephants,</hi> and <hi>Tigers,</hi> and <hi>Bears:</hi> They firſt granted their Licenſes to the <hi>Stages,</hi> to delude, and cheat, and deſtroy the People.
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:38982:7"/>Our glorious Patron of Learning, <hi>K. Henry</hi> VIII. the Lords and Commons, (<hi>Ann. Dom.</hi> 1524.) Eſtabliſh'd, by Law, the College, and the Surgeons Company, avow in the Act, that they dread the moſt publick Calamities impending on the Nation, if they expoſe the Life of the Subjects to Undertakers, not examin'd whether they underſtand the in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>numerable Diſeaſes, and the cautious Uſe of the Medicines. <hi>Secondly,</hi> If the Adviſers receive their Reward from their Arbitrary Numbers and Rates of the Doſes, obtruded on all Diſorders whatſoever. Wou'd to God, Committees of the Nobility, Gentry, and Clergy, were ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed to ſit, till they had collected all the Calamities, which the Sick from the Numbers of Doſes in all the Diſeaſes and Conſtitutions muſt ſuffer. In that and the following Reigns, the <hi>Kings</hi> in <hi>Council,</hi> the <hi>Lord Chamberlain,</hi> the <hi>Judges,</hi> frequently animated the College, to the moſt vigilant Detection of the <hi>Empiricks,</hi> often commanded the <hi>Lord Mayor,</hi> the <hi>Juſtices,</hi> to aſſiſt the <hi>Cenſors</hi> in their Apprehenſion and Puniſhment. The Society is compos'd of the Graduates from our famous Univerſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, which can only give the Lauguages, the Philoſophy, the Rudi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments of the Art, but muſt be advanc'd to the greateſt Perfection in the moſt popoulous City, which preſents Millions of Caſes, the moſt diligent Attendance, the Reports to one another of the ſalutary or unhappy Succeſs of the moſt different Methods and Medicines. The Nobility and Gentry meet in the two Houſes of Parliament to debate <hi>de arduis Regni Negotiis,</hi> the Phyſicians mutually impart and receive in the endow'd Lectures, and their Conferences, their Obſervations of the moſt difficult Diſeaſes, the Triumphs of the Specifick Remedies. There is nothing can baſſle the moſt wiſe Eſtabliſhment of the College, but the Arrogance of the Phyſician, who aſſumes to himſelf, as our <hi>Prophets,</hi> the whole Art of raiſing his Patients, as from the Grave, has monopo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liz'd the Science of all things paſt, preſent, and to come, affirms all So<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cieties are uſeleſs. But in the Reign of K. <hi>James</hi> I. (<hi>Ann Dom</hi> 1616.) all the legal Eſtabliſhments were overturn'd by the <hi>Grants</hi> bought of the Cour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiers, to invade all the Profeſſions and Arts. Then 114 Apothecaries obtain a <hi>Charter</hi> to deal only in Medicines. The <hi>Waters, Spirits, Tinctures,</hi> had been ſold by the <hi>Diſtillers.</hi> The <hi>Confections, Powders, Pills, Oyntments, Plaiſters,</hi> by the <hi>Grocers,</hi> who ſold the <hi>Spices, Fruits</hi> and <hi>Drugs,</hi> and the Medicines in the large Quantities to the Families, who had learn'd the Mixtures of the Waters, and the Diviſions of the others into Doſes from their Phyſicians Inſtructions.</p>
               <p>My dear <hi>Britains.</hi> I aſſure you, Providence can never fail in the abun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dant Proviſion of all things neceſſary to ſupport Life. Have the Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple the Property, and the juſt Right and Demand of our Care of the Plenty of Bread and the other Foods? The moſt ſovereign Medicines are equally the eaſie Purchaſe of the Poor, or the Charity of the Wealthy. I appeal to your Experience of the Medicines prepar'd in the Houſes; of the Quantities bought of the Apothecary, Chymiſt, Drug<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giſt, or the Compoſitions imported by the Merchants, of our Hoſpitals, where many thouſand Patients are yearly medicin'd at the Expence of a Nobleman's Family. But the Phyſician's Fee is more affrighting than the Pain or Fear of Death. But our <hi>Kings,</hi> the <hi>Miniſters</hi> of <hi>State,</hi> the <hi>Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficers</hi> of the <hi>Fleet</hi> and <hi>Army,</hi> the <hi>Judges,</hi> the <hi>Clergy,</hi> have their Fees from the proportion'd Taxations of all the Conditions; and the <hi>Nobility</hi> and <hi>Gentry,</hi> receive the little Payments of the <hi>Cottages</hi> of their <hi>Mannors.</hi> The Fees of the <hi>Nobility</hi> and <hi>Gentry</hi> can have no Bounds, but all the Populace cheerfully preſented their Gratuities proportion'd to their Circumſtan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces, but with the ineſtimable Preſents of the innumerable Diſeaſes, which daily increaſe the Treaſure of the Phyſicians Knowledge. The Nobi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lity,
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:38982:7"/>
                  <hi>&amp;c.</hi> The Merchants, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> then gave their Phyſicians their propor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion'd Salaries. The Phyſicians then near their Houſes, (warranted by their learned Education, and the Examination and Applauſe of the College) were tortur'd by their greateſt Intereſt to ſubdue the Diſeaſe in its Invaſion, abate the Malignity of the Fevers, and often overcome them in 3 or 4 Days, to prevent the neceſſary Attendance of the Mor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nings and Evenings of the tedious Courſe. Their Intereſt compell'd them to communicate the cautious Uſe of the moſt excellent Medicines in the frequent ſafe incidental Diſeaſes of the Families. The vitious ſophiſticated Medicines were prevented or expell'd from the Chambers. Will you be ſurpriz'd, when I affirm, that the Phyſicians adviſing all the Sick, and the numerous Diſtempers near them, ſhall in few Years acquire a Science ten thouſand times more eſtimable than the Moderns can preſume? They obſerv'd all the Acute and Chronical Diſeaſes, as the Gardner his Plants riſing out of the Earth; and, as a Pilot at the Helm, had no Oppoſition from any ſeparate or contrary Intereſt, and were in all the Diſſiculties aſſiſted by the Council of the moſt generous Patrons, who bequeathed the <hi>Arcana</hi> of the Diſeaſes and Remedies their Predeceſſors had left them. Will it be objected, we purſue our Lux<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uries and our Avarice beyond all the Univerſe, but then in the intervals, we are the braveſt, and wiſeſt, and moſt publick Spirited, outdo all in Improvements of Wit, and Pleaſures, and Manufactures: Our Phy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſicians and Surgeons, (tho' in the great Aſſemblies we deſpiſe and abhor them) are imagin'd from their imprudent Prattel in the Publick Houſes the greateſt Artiſts of <hi>Europe.</hi> We have often (my dear United <hi>Britains</hi>) fought for Plunder on the Borders; here I defie you, as the Princes of old conteſted the Diſcoveries the moſt uſeful and Royal. Our Phyſici<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ans demonſtrate, that the Philoſophy of Nature has but lately advanc'd Northward, has been inſulted in its Progreſs by the fierce Diſputes of imaginary and impertinent Notions, by the Hypotheſes of Principles and Corpuſcles above the Reach of their Senſes and Underſtanding. Phyſick, which claims the Honours and Prerogatives from employing the Philoſophy of all Nature to the Divine End of preſerving Health and Life, was the Purſuit of all the Princes, Nobility, Philoſophers, after the firſt Affright of Diſeaſes. They collected all the Obſervations of the Powers of all the Natural Cauſes and Energies, invading or pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tecting Mankind. <hi>Hippocrates</hi> and <hi>Galen, &amp;c.</hi> collected all the funda<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mental, infallible, univerſally receiv'd Laws of Phyſick, diverſify'd, as the <hi>Governments,</hi> by the various Climates, and Manners, and Diet. The Eſtabliſhment of the Royal College, deſign'd the Detection of the Diſeaſes from our Climate, Air, Manners, and Diet, the Adjuſtment to them of the Methods of Cure, and the Qualities of the Medicines ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prov'd by the numerous Ages. The barbarous Irruption of Empiriciſm, as of the <hi>Goths</hi> and <hi>Vandals,</hi> has broken almoſt all the Attempts. Dr. <hi>Sydenham</hi> reviv'd the vaſt Enterprize, by the Care of all the Sick in his Province, comparing the Impreſſions of all the Diſeaſes, the Efforts and Tendencies of Nature, (the firſt and moſt powerful, and moſt ſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>licitous Agent in all the Diſeaſes) where its Symptoms promiſe and operate the never-failing Recovery, where it craves to be aſſiſted, dire<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cted or moderated, or oppos'd. Hiſtory gives the ſureſt Inſtructions to all the Governments in Peace and War. The Conduct of Diſeaſes, the Uſes of almoſt all the Parts of the Univerſe to prevent or conquer them, are to be addreſs'd to the peculiar Conſtitutions of the diſtant Nations from the great Magazines of their Succeſs. But we muſt imi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tate the Ancients in their Sincerity and Induſtry. Our Phyſicians had the little, but mighty and moſt neceſſary Artifice almoſt peculiar to
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:38982:8"/>themſelves; had the proportion'd Fee in the Morning, but to prevent the mortal Suſpicions, aſſum'd the frequent Viſits moſt neceſſary in the moſt acute and impending Dangers. How often did they preſerve the Patients, and enrich their Knowledge by the hourly Views of Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plexies, profuſe Vomiting, Purging, Bleeding, when they remarkt the Operations of the Medicines, directed more powerful, or more feeble, when they ſaw the Approaches of new and contrary Symptoms? I have been aſſur'd by my Phyſicians of Honour and Virtue, that the firſt De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>grees of all Diſeaſes, which can affect Mankind, are ſafe, the appearing fierce and painful Symptoms often enſure the Life, the Efforts of Nature directed, not repell'd and deſtroy'd, but the advanc'd Degrees of all the Diſtempers are as fatal as the Peſtilence. Our Phyſicians than could hear or ſee the firſt Signals of Danger. They did not in the firſt Moments decree the Methods of Bleeding, Vomiting, Purging, the 8 or 10 ſweating Doſes for the ſucceeding 24 Hours. But they warily obſerv'd the Pulſe, the Heat, the natural Evacuations by the Pores, Urine, or the Bowels; the next View demonſtrated the Blood now de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>purating it ſelf, the Salutary Evacuation begun, or the continued Eva<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuation rejecting the morbid Humors, abating the Fury of the Diſeaſe, and promiſing the Victory. The other Artifice produces its wonderful Effects. The different Conditions gave the half Fee in the Chronical Diſeaſes at the Phyſicians Houſe. They did not adviſe the poor Gentle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men at the Tipling-Houſes, without the Informations of the Urine, an Hour before a Part of the Blood, and the ſureſt Meſſenger from it, ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>amin'd with the other Evidences.</p>
               <p>Shall we then, my dear <hi>South Britains,</hi> conclude with the Gentlemen of Quality and the Remonſtrance of the College in the <hi>Poem,</hi> that the Modern Phyſick is a Dangerous Craft, and put it down, as the <hi>Roy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>al-Oak-Lottery,</hi> or reſtore it to its Integrity and Sufficiency. The Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eaſe is known, and the Remedy moſt obvious, the exceſſive diſpropor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion'd increaſe of the Apothecaries, and the Oppreſſive Invaſion of their Property by the infinite Empiries. In all the wiſe Government in <hi>Europe</hi> they are prevented from their multiplication pernicious to themſelves and the Profeſſion and People. The 114 in the <hi>Charter</hi> (<hi>An.</hi> 1616.) increaſt by the 2 or 3 Prentices in every ſhop, had fill'd all the ſtreets of the City and the Villages about it. In their Diſtreſs from the Incroachments of the Quacks and themſelves, the Court-Phyſicians, and a ſmall part then of the Collegiates propos'd to go ſnacks with them, taking the half of the 20 or 30, or 40 <hi>l.</hi> from all the Fevers and the Small-Pox, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> the moſt eaſie and ſecure, as the moſt perplex'd and hazar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dous, and 100 or 200 <hi>l.</hi> in the long Diſorders. How can it be? But what cannot the combination of 2 Artiſts atchieve? The vulgar Medicines are only to be us'd; the Cordials, Sweaters, Sleepers, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Inſtead of their Mixtures and Diviſions in the Family from the then known and cheap Quantities, all muſt be parted by the Apothecary into little Doſes. They are diſguis'd from their Knowledge by contriv'd Pompous Names, in the Latin Preſcription. Every Doſe muſt be pretended to be a rare and pretious thing, all the Boles and Powders avow'd to be compounded with <hi>Bezoar,</hi> tho' the ten thouſandth Part is not im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ported, and all the Juleps in all Diſorders muſt be enrich'd with <hi>Perle,</hi> inferior to many of the moſt plentiful <hi>Alkalies.</hi> That the Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcript may ſwell to the admired Bulk and Grandeur, the common Me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dicines, which are each perfect and compleat for the reſpective Intentions, muſt be jumbled together 20 or 40 in each Doſe, whoſe In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gredients may make 300 or 400 Drugs in each <hi>Medicine.</hi> You ſee My dear <hi>South Britains,</hi> That the firſt Great Law of Nature is violated, that,
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:38982:8"/>as the <hi>Bark,</hi> its Soveraign Medicines in all the other Afflictions <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>hall not be affronted and diſturbed by the abſurd additions, which <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ertainly make the benign Diſtempers moſt fatal, and the dangerous moſt deadly. The Phyſicians and Surgeons then confeſt, that <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>hey kill'd the Patients and their Arts and Societies, but they would <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>aſt their Time, they had the greater Fee for the Morning Viſit only, they had the enjoyment of good Company. The Apothecaries had the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>are of the Symptoms of the Evening and Night, the Medicines muſt be taken at the appointed Hours, or new directed by them, or from their Report of the greater or new Diſtreſs to the Phyſician. The Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpirators generouſly beſtow'd the meaner Patients on the Apothecaries, and aſſum'd the Grandeur of treating only the Diſeaſes of Quality and Wealth. But when the terrible Payments of the Bill made the Fees inſupportable, the Houſes were compell'd to uſe the Apothecaries in all Caſes, till the Life is deſpair'd of, who then appoint the moſt choice Phy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſician. Is it not inevitable, that the Men of the Character of the <hi>Mir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mils, Querpo's,</hi> and the <hi>Bards,</hi> ſhall atteſt that there is no Omiſſion or Commiſſion in the Method of Cure the Patient has been under, that they communicate their Knowledge and all their Medicines? They ſhall be diſcarded if they abate the number of the Doſes of the now 30 vulgar Medicines of the Shop, if they preſume to reſtore the Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>propriate Specificks, which muſt govern the Cure of Diſeaſes. It is not impoſſible (my <hi>BRITAINS</hi>) to find out the Redreſs of your Cala<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mities; Your Anceſtors have reſerv'd many of the infallible Medicines long ſince abdicated, and thy have bequeathed to you their care of the Publick, and their Wiſdom to preſerve it. Their firſt care was to ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>port the Fidelity, and Induſtry, to improve the Science of the young Phyſicians, warranted to the People, as the Judges of the Circuits, as the Coins and Meaſures. The Charters preclude the Hoſpitals from uſurping the Diſeaſes from the Phyſicians and Surgeons care. They are commanded to receive only the maim'd and wounded Seamen and Soldiers, or the Caſualties of the City: They foreſaw the Dangers of the Diſeas'd from the rude conveyance to them: from the ſtench of the Rooms, by the exceſſive Numbers, and the Scents of Dreſſings: from the Sleep broken, by the Groans of the Pain'd and Departing, and the cla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>morous Attendance: from the groſs Diet as in the Houſes of Labour: from the uſe of the vulgar Remedies only, and the ſuſpected cruel Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſal of the juſt Proportions: from the rare and confus'd Advices of the Phyſicians and Surgeons. The Clergy, who in the Spittal Sermons, re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>port the Reſtrictions of their Charity to the wounded and maim'd, will revive in the Citizens the Ancient Uſage, when the Poor were ſaved by the hourly care of their Phyſicians and Surgeons, obſerving the tendency of each Diſeaſe, and the Powers of the Remedies, with the affectionate Attendance of the Houſes, the undiſturbed Repoſes in the Air not corrupted, the Diet adjuſted to all the Conſtitutions, and the ſteady uſe of the Specifick Medicines. This Charity will introduce the Rewards given to the Phyſicians and Surgeons in all the Cities of <hi>Eu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rope,</hi> with the Aſſurance, that this Method only can raiſe Phyſick and Surgery to the greateſt Perfection, and the Applauſes of the Calami<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tous near them reliev'd by their Bounty. The Univerſities and the Clergy will animate your Zeal to protect the Profeſſions eſtabliſh'd by Law. The College has in the <hi>Poem</hi> humby propos'd, That the weighty Affair may be examin'd and judg'd by <hi>Viſitors,</hi> who will command the ſurrender of the Phyſicians and Surgeons, and Apothecaries Charters that Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tutes ſhall be adjuſted, which ſhall not be broken by their mutual rage and the abhorr'd Apoſtaſies of their Members. We may fix the neceſſary
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:38982:9"/>Boundaries from the Laws the Eaſtern Emperours and Miniſters <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> State Religouſly obſerve, who muſt, every Year, hear an Hour one of all the Profeſſions and Trades. In the mean time, the Phyſicians and Surgeons, muſt moſt induſtriouſly diſcover the innumerable Circumſtances of all the Diſeaſes, muſt examine the Qualities, and Vertues, and Preparations of all the Medicines. Then the Government will view with Pleaſure, when it ſhall reſtore the Societies, (as when the Univerſe was form'd from no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing,) the Beauty, and Goodneſs, and Harmony of the Parts. The Harangue on St. <hi>Luke</hi>'s <hi>Day,</hi> will entertain the Audience, that we have at laſt begun to apply the Sacred Truths, the Obſervations of many Ages, collected by the famous Greek and Latin Authors, to the Britiſh Diſeaſes, whoſe Language and moſt uſeful Philoſophy has not been un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derſtood by our moſt eminent Practiſers. Will the Orator be able to perſuade, that in <hi>England,</hi> the Advice for Nothing had undone the Poor in every Sickneſs by the Sovereign Medicines, ten times cheaper than their Food: that it rais'd the Apothecaries and the Empiricks on the Ruin of Phyſick and Surgery, who are elevated and ſunk by the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thecaries, and muſt therefore, with the moſt infamous Treachery, aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſault and deſtroy one the other, and their Profeſſions: That the Phy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſicians and Surgeons near the Court, had never ſeen the Riſe and Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>greſs of any Diſeaſe, had tamper'd only with the common Receipts of 30 vulgar Remedies, almoſt always fatal to the Royal Family, the Nobility, and Millions of the People? How will they be ſurpriz'd, that an hundred Years had paſt, during the Sales of Patents and Char<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters, and the Rebellion, and, after the Reſtoration, and the more perni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cious Civil-War of our Follies and Vices, before the Collegiates could convince the Nation, that the Right and Property in the Plenty of all the Remedies, and the Protection of their Life, can only be reſtor'd by the Defence of the Apothecaries againſt the Deluge of the Native and the Foreign Empiricks, and the Regulation of the Number of their Shops?</p>
            </div>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:38982:9"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
